[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
[♪ tense music playing]
[panting]
[exclaims]
[gasps]
[Kitae] Mr. President.
Uh, sir?
[door slams]
[pants]
Kitae.
-Don't touch me!
-[gasps]
What's going on?
Is he dead?
-Yes.
-[gasps]
It was Cho, wasn't it?
Yeah.
Cho, that lunatic!
[breathing heavily]
I knew he was going to do something.
But to murder the President…
him and Chief Gwak…
[breathing heavily]
What happened to Director Cho?
OCTOBER 27,
MILITARY SECURITY COMMAND
PRESIDENTIAL ASSASSINATION…
[sighs]
Deputy Director, good afternoon.
I've been assigned to this investigation.
I'm Lieutenant Colonel Baek.
STYLE
::cue()
You were at the Gungjeong-dong safe house
after the incident, is that correct?
[slurping]
So why did you show up there?
Your name wasn't
on the guest list for the dinner.
[phone rings]
What time did you arrive last night?
Colonel Ahn Jaeho.
We're beginning the process.
[Kihyun] Who did you come with?
Yes, sir. But, is there…
a specific reason Colonel Baek was, um,
assigned to this post?
Deputy Director,
were you involved
in the President's murder?
If you would prefer to sit here
and remain silent,
we'll assume that you're admitting
to criminal charges.
Is that what you want?
What are you doing? Who made you do this?
Deputy Director…
Look, I think maybe
you're not grasping this…
Your superior shot and killed
the President and you were there!
Ugh, I'm full.
[sighs]
[Kitae clears throat]
Hey, you in there!
Can you hear me?
Listen carefully.
Call up General Jang Mujin.
Do it immediately.
And ask him who captured Director Cho.
All right?
[phone rings]
Baek Kitae is being questioned
by the Joint Investigation Headquarters?
Yes, sir. We heard he was
in Gungjeong-dong that evening.
[Mujin] Yeah, that's right.
…JANG MUJIN
Actually saw him myself at the safe house.
That's why I called you.
We'd just like a chance to
ask some questions, sir.
It won't take long, sir, I promise.
What do you need to question him for?
Colonel Ahn, listen here.
I'm listening, sir.
Release the Deputy Director.
-We can't just let him go without--
-Stop it!
He's the one who captured Director Cho!
What?
If it weren't for him,
this country would be
in Cho's hands right now.
You're telling me…
you really think I was involved
in assassinating the President?
I look like Director Cho to you?
That power-tripping piece of shit.
Get your head straight, Baek Kihyun.
Think carefully about who's on your side.
Who's your friend,
and who's your adversary…
[Kitae sighs]
Deputy Director, sir…
you can leave now.
[Kitae scoffs]
[Jaeho] Let him through.
Sir, what happened?
He was the person
who captured Director Cho.
[sighs]
[♪ inquisitive music playing]
STYLE
::cue()
KOREAN CENTRAL
INTELLIGENCE AGENCY
[Kitae] Sometimes, one split-second
decision changes the course of history.
Sir, wait!
Sir!
-Wait, sir!
-[tires screech]
-What?
-[Kitae] Sir.
Tell me where you're heading.
Well, I'm going to the KCIA.
And what are you planning to do?
Uh… I… I don't know.
[scoffs] Wait a minute.
Hang on.
So all of the gunshots I heard earlier…
Wait… The President is safe, isn't he?
[Kitae] Before assassinating
the President,
Director Cho had summoned
Army Chief of Staff, Jang Mujin,
to the government safe house.
His plan was to take Mujin to KCIA
headquarters after the job was finished,
-and convince him to join his side.
-[breathing shakily]
Mr. Cho, please…
Report to Army headquarters.
Army headquarters?
You'll need the support
of the entire military.
Go to Army headquarters.
Both of you wait there.
I'll take care of everything at the KCIA.
Good plan, we'll drive over now.
You handle the KCIA.
[pants] Don't worry about a thing.
Make sure you get there quickly.
I'll call you ASAP, sir.
[Cho] Let's go! To the Army headquarters!
[Kitae] However, after the deed was done,
Cho started panicking.
-In the end, he decided to trust me…
-[sighs]
…and headed straight to the
Army headquarters instead of the KCIA.
This is KCIA Deputy Director Baek Kitae.
Director Cho killed the President.
He's on his way to Army headquarters now.
As soon as he gets there,
you need to arrest him.
Cho murdered the president,
are you listening?
Arrest him now!
Incompetent son of a bitch.
DEPUTY DIRECTOR BAEK KITAE
[Mujin] You've done an excellent job,
Deputy Director Baek.
-Well done.
-I was just doing my duty.
The KCIA was implicated in this,
so they'll bring in
Joint Investigations for the inquiry.
That concerns me.
A boat that's being rocked
is bound to wind up on the ocean floor.
Yes, of course.
Your concerns make sense,
especially in this climate.
Mr. Baek.
Effective immediately,
I am appointing you acting director
of the Korean Central Intelligence Agency.
I'm very flattered, sir.
Deputy Director… Oh, sorry.
Director Baek, please don't let me down.
Hwang Daesik will take over
unless we act fast.
-That man can't be allowed near power.
-Understood, sir.
[♪ sinister music playing]
[sighs]
PERSONAL DETAILS
BAEK KITAE
Baek Kitae's the one
who captured Director Cho?
Yes, sir.
Cho was headed to the KCIA,
then Baek lured him away.
Ah… That prick.
He's pretty clever.
Guess there's a reason
he was such an asset to the President.
He's acting director now.
He was appointed by
General Jang Mujin this morning.
Okay, so General Jang's
trying to keep us in check. [sighs]
Any other intel
from the guy who brought this?
STYLE
::cue()
-Yes, sir.
-What did he say?
He's going after Chief Cheon's funding.
All the money
he's getting from the government.
[laughs]
That son of a bitch
is pretty clever too, huh?
[Hwang inhales sharply]
He's getting out soon.
At least that's what I've heard.
Yes, speaking of which,
it's about time
he got into the game again.
For real this time. Don't you think?
Agreed.
For real this time. That's right.
Get him a position
in the Joint Investigation Headquarters.
Yes, will do, sir.
[inhales sharply]
Jaeho, listen.
Sir?
You need to realize…
that this assassination is…
nothing less than
an opportunity from heaven.
-[laughs]
-[Jaeho] At this time,
head of Martial Law Joint
Investigation Headquarters, Hwang Daesik
will deliver an interim briefing
on the assassination of the President.
The assassination of the President,
which took place at 7:50 p.m.,
on October 26th in a safe house
in the Gungjeong-dong area,
was tragically committed in a banquet hall
where KCIA officials met
to discuss matters of national security.
This murder was determined
to be premeditated
and carried out by
Mr. Cho Namsik of the KCIA.
The motive was Cho's fear of dismissal.
He had recently lost the president's trust
and was under scrutiny
by the Presidential Security Service.
His ambition was to seize authority,
and become president himself.
His lust for power and control
drove him to commit this monstrous act.
Right now!
Right here!
The KCIA is standing at
the greatest crossroads since inception.
This agency was built with the blood
and sweat of our people
and now we're losing their trust!
Our very name…
Mocked and ridiculed at every turn.
From this day on,
our agency will thrive under my command.
We'll restore our power,
and we will protect
the reputation of the state!
If we want to survive, this is how.
And that will secure
the future of our great nation.
We consider this the greatest tragedy
and most grievous offense
ever committed under the Yushin regime.
In order for us to reestablish
our national security,
all available resources
will be mobilized to prevent recurrence.
We will…
-We will…
…work in the shadows!
-…work in the shadows!
…to defend our sunlit land!
-…to defend our sunlit land!
-Commander!
-General Hwang, sir!
Do you have anything to say?
Please, just a brief comment, general!
[Kitae] Hwang Daesik, head of
the Joint Investigation Headquarters,
will use his investigative powers
to tear the KCIA apart
and rise to the center of power.
As acting director of the KCIA,
I must find a way
to contain the situation,
stop Hwang from taking over,
and reclaim the KCIA's authority.
That's right.
The KCIA and the JIH
are in a full-blown dogfight.
To our country and its people!
-Here, here!
[exclaims]
[chanting] Hwang Daesik!
-Hwang Daesik!
STYLE
::cue()
The President's dead
and it's time to move forward.
What matters now is…
who comes next.
Who's gonna take his seat
and lead this country?
Who do you think will do it?
Someone once said,
"Kings are only chosen by the heavens."
And I think
you might be heaven's selection.
[chuckles] Come on, what is that?
Hwang's not about to sit and do nothing.
At this point, he's our biggest problem.
That bald, oily son of a bitch.
He just wants status and control.
All of the power and authority
can be found in
the Joint Investigation Headquarters.
Hwang will use the investigation
to eliminate his political enemies.
Ah, shit.
So they'll likely take aim
right at the KCIA from the start.
Exactly.
Which means you and I are both gonna be
on his list of targets to get rid of.
So what's the plan, Baek?
You gonna let it happen?
You gonna just sit there and take it?
[inhales deeply] Well, sir.
Why don't we…
cross the Rubicon together? Join forces.
[♪ tense music playing]
You mean you want us to…
overthrow the government?
You know how this country is structured.
You've seen it,
from the inside, with the President.
[sighs]
[sighs, grunts]
[♪ thrilling music playing]
[sighs] Let's do it.
Yeah. Let's be bold!
-[Kitae applauds]
-[sighs]
First off,
we need to win over
General Jang's support.
Ugh, well he's not exactly
a pushover, is he?
We need the Martial Law Commander
on our side
if we're going to take over the military.
I know.
And we'll get there.
But first, talk to Choi.
Have her bring the money
I entrusted to her.
You ever seen anyone turn down money?
Those Army bastards…
They lose their minds
at the smell of clean cash.
All we have to do is buy them off.
Right. Copy that.
Kitae, look.
I 'm counting on you now, all right?
And you know…
after I move up, you're next.
BUSAN DISTRICT
PROSECUTORS' OFFICE
-[humming]
-[indistinct chattering on TV]
-[reporter] Director Cho announced that…
-[sighs]
-…would mobilize every resource…
-What does this mean?
STYLE
::cue()
…at its disposal
to reestablish national discipline
and prevent any further political violence
or unrest in the coming weeks.
Major General Hwang's promise
to the Korean people
-comes amidst widespread complaints…
-Good morning, ma'am.
…of abuse by the--
Taking a break?
Come on, let's go.
Get back to work. Now!
-Yes, ma'am.
-Let's get back to it.
[sighing, muttering]
[Yejin sighs]
-Kang, over here.
-Yeah, coming.
So Park Changbae,
have you located him yet?
Oh, uh, we're using Kim's statement to
get a general area, then narrow it down,
but he's in Seoul, not Busan,
so it's a bit harder.
Uh, and Ms. Oh,
the chief told us to bury this case.
If he finds out about this,
he's going to blow his top.
-You sure this is okay?
-[phone rings]
-[investigator] Narcotics Unit, Busan…
-[Yejin] All right, Changbae,
-where are you?
-[investigator] She's here. Understood.
Sorry, excuse me, uh…
The chief wants to see you upstairs.
Yes.
[Yejin] "Integrity, honesty, humility."
Wow, Chief. That's a really nice
sentiment for what it's worth.
[Yejin chuckles]
You know, Ms. Oh… [sighs]
…it occurred to me that
even though you've been here a while,
I've never treated you to a cup of tea
in my office, not to mention…
you're the first female prosecutor
in Korean history.
-I should be offering more.
-[chuckles]
Man or woman, male or female,
we're all prosecutors…
We all have the same title.
Hmm…
[both sigh]
So, um,
why am I in the principal's office?
Mmm…
The Joint Investigation Headquarters
is asking us to stop the criminals
who are causing social unrest.
You hear about this?
Yes, sounds familiar.
[inhales sharply] Although, I don't…
I don't know why it'd be their purview
to look into something like that, do you?
Well, they'd probably say something like,
"We are in an unprecedented
time of crisis,
so if we want to prevent further unrest,
prosecutors should expand
the scope of their job
as a duty to the country."
Anyway, on that note,
remember that narcotics case you had?
The one that's been shut down for a while…
You wanna maybe reopen it?
All of a sudden?
Why? Why reopen it?
Well, it was your case originally, right?
Yeah, sure. It was, but still, sir…
Was this an order you got
from a director way up the flagpole?
What are you talking about, Ms. Oh?
We're supposed to be
prosecuting drug crimes, regardless.
And if we're gonna do it,
might as well go for broke.
We'll support with every resource
our office can give.
Do you mean that, sir?
Please don't be generous
if you're gonna go back on your word
and break your promise.
Hey. Have I ever done that, Ms. Oh?
Yes, many times.
[sighs]
I'm serious in this case.
The people at Joint Investigations
need a prosecutor,
and they specifically requested you.
Is that a joke?
No.
Why me though?
How should I know?
But… Mmm…
You happen to know someone there?
Over at the JIH?
Not at all.
[gasps] Whoa.
JOINT INVESTIGATION HEADQUARTERS
INVESTIGATION DIVISION
[clears throat]
[Jaeho] Investigate thoroughly
and tell your men to keep security tight.
-Understood?
-[soldiers] Yes, sir.
STYLE
::cue()
Prosecutor Oh Yejin?
I'm Colonel Ahn,
Chief of Security Department.
Oh Yejin, nice to meet you.
This way.
You can wait here, Ms. Oh.
Ah, also…
I've heard positive things
from the advisor.
I'm excited to work with you.
The advisor?
He'll be here in a moment.
[sighs]
Geez, could they make it
any darker in here?
Looks like a damn crypt.
SPECIAL ADVISOR JANG GEONYOUNG
Congratulations
on the promotion, Director.
So, what are you doing in Seoul?
Well, they transferred me
as deputy director.
They promoted you,
so your old job opened up.
I'm your replacement.
You're number one, and I'm number two.
Hang on.
Chief Cheon didn't tell you, did he?
[chuckles] Sorry.
I just assumed you already knew.
He really didn't discuss it with you
at all?
Wow. Man.
That's not right.
He screwed up on that one.
[sighs]
It's a big office.
Well, I'm sure he had his reasons
for bringing you in.
So do your job well.
And stay out of trouble.
Yes, sir. Director.
Oh, by the way,
I heard you got interrogated.
Hauled you
into Joint Investigation Headquarters.
Sounds like
General Hwang's out to get you.
Know what people have
been calling him lately?
The Bald Rhino.
Correct! [chuckles]
He's so determined that he'll bulldoze
over everything in his way
to get what he wants.
He throws all his weight at the problem
and rams ahead until he reaches his goal.
He's bald, too, so yeah.
Lot of bald guys are like that.
But honestly, here's the problem.
The agency's rep has
been pretty bad lately.
You really think we can win against Hwang?
What do you think, sir?
Hmm?
Want me to send you back to Busan?
'Cause it's starting to feel like
you're here to antagonize me.
Well?
Hey.
Pyo Haksu.
You bald little rat.
Yes, Kitae?
"Yes, sir."
Sir, I'm sorry.
You better get it together.
Understood, I'm very sorry.
STYLE
::cue()
CHIEF OF SECURITY DEPARTMENT
AHN JAEHO
-Ah, you're here.
-Oh. Let me get that, sir.
Oh, yeah, thanks.
-What's this box for?
-[door closes]
Oh, that?
Ah, well,
Chief Cheon's slush fund,
we're keeping a paper trail on it.
You want the assignment?
Is there some reason you're choosing me?
Well, you're…
you're the smartest one here.
It's true.
Special orders from the commander,
so be diligent, all right?
Go through these, figure out
the full extent of the slush fund
and report back.
Yes, sir. Of course.
[door opens]
MILITARY SECURITY COMMAND
PERSONAL RECORD - 1. PERSONAL
DETAILS - NAME: BAEK KITAE
9 YEARS EARLIER, BUSAN
I heard you joined Security Command.
Tell me why you asked to see me, sir.
What did Jang Geonyoung say
when he visited you?
Did you see me in Saigon? See what I did?
Yes, I remember.
So what are you going to do now?
Try to take me down?
Look, Kihyun.
You need to choose.
If I did come after you,
what would you do about it?
Well, if it weren't for me,
you think you'd be where you are now?
What?
Am I wrong here?
You threatening me?
I won't consider you family
if you decide to get aggressive with this.
Either you go down, or I do.
Or maybe we both will.
So I would think of your family
when you're choosing
which route to take here.
Just like I did
for Soyeong
and for you.
[sighs]
[♪ classical music playing]
Who was it anyway?
STYLE
::cue()
Who exactly ordered my interrogation?
Colonel Ahn gave the assignment.
[scoffs]
So he put you to the test
to see how you'd react.
Any other information?
He hasn't said very much.
They'll keep pressuring you,
the Joint Investigation Headquarters.
Know what I mean, Kihyun?
Oh, by the way,
there's something I need you to do.
Keep close tabs on what happens
at the JIH and report back to me.
So I'm supposed to act as your mole now?
The fact is we're at war.
And it won't end until one side falls.
Our whole family will go down
if I'm the one who falls.
It's amazing how you always do this.
You can't hold our family captive forever.
Are you saying
you want to go against me?
[thudding]
[phone ringing]
I've got the money ready.
How long 'til it gets here?
Around two days. I'm gonna bring it.
You mean you personally?
Of course. It's a hefty sum.
Besides, we have some things to discuss.
Really? Like what?
Well, martial law's putting quite a dent
in our sales.
So we better strategize.
All right, then. I'll be waiting for you.
-Morning, sir!
-[door closes]
What, Captain Min?
Oh. You're needed
at Joint Investigation Headquarters.
-The Colonel requested your presence.
-Really?
Yes, sir.
Is there something else?
STYLE
::cue()
Uh…
Rumor is they've been planning
to increase their personnel.
And?
Would you recommend me?
I heard about you
from the Busan Prosecutors' Office.
You're kinda famous over there.
Nah, that's really not true.
I keep the wheels turning, that's all.
Just try to keep the place on track.
-Smooth things over.
-Mm-hmm.
Well, that's not what I heard.
-There are some colorful stories.
-[chuckles]
Oh, really?
They say I'm outta my goddamn mind?
[laughs]
-[coughing]
-Hear that?
[laughing]
That funny to you?
-Uh, no. It's, uh, not funny at all.
-[investigator] Hey, hand me that stapler.
[Jaeho] No, no, sorry, uh…
No one said you're crazy really.
More like prone to impulsivity, reckless.
Look, I have self-control.
I just don't like to bother with it.
Am I supposed to be a hall monitor
or am I supposed to bust criminals?
-Who cares how I do it?
-Just like I heard.
You've got a big pair of balls on you.
Ah. There he is.
Oh, Colonel Baek!
Say hello.
She works
in the Busan District Prosecutors' Office.
Oh Yejin. It's a pleasure.
Baek Kihyun, ma'am.
Nice to meet you. How's your sister?
You know her? You two met?
Yeah, in Busan, I knew her…
[chuckles] …not super well,
just a little bit.
I see.
[Kang] Yeah, all right.
Okay, Ms. Oh, everything's ready.
We should head out now.
Uh-huh. Let's move then.
See you around, Mr. Baek.
All right, move it!
-Okay.
-Yes, ma'am.
-[investigator] Goodbye.
-[Kang] Hey, grab the radios.
This way. There's someone you should meet.
Close the door.
Have a seat.
So who am I meeting?
Well actually, you know him already.
He'll be here soon.
So let's have a smoke while we're waiting.
Sure.
[lighter ignites]
Let's see.
All right. We've got a few minutes.
-Sir.
-Thanks.
Here.
The raw materials are coming today,
you're sure?
Yes, I'm sure.
STYLE
::cue()
[Haksu] I heard you're going to Busan.
Why make the trip, sir?
I've got some business.
What kind?
Do I have to tell you everything?
Just making conversation.
-[knocks on door]
-[door opens]
Director, the car is ready for you.
Okay.
You're going along?
Yes.
You never even called
once you moved to Seoul.
I apologize.
I've been getting settled in Seoul.
-I'm busy.
-You goddamn little shit.
-Sir?
-What's with your tone?
What about my tone?
-Hey!
-You…
The hell are you doing?
Do what I told you. I expect some results.
Yes, Mr. Baek, sir.
-Let's go.
-I'll see you when you're back.
[door opens]
[in English] Boys,
be ambitious!
[line ringing]
It's Haksu. Hello.
1:08 A.M., BUSAN
Okay. They're on the move.
1:15 A.M., SEOUL
Ms. Oh. They just arrived.
[shutters clicking]
BAEKHO TRADING INC.
[shutters continue clicking]
1:38 A.M., BUSAN
What's your plan now?
What's all this money going to be for?
Patriotism.
How? With a showdown?
You gonna start some kind of gunfight?
Well, I've come this far.
Can't stop now.
Are you sure you can pull it off?
Honestly, I'm not sure that matters.
All that matters in a gunfight is
who's faster on the draw.
[soldier] Open fire!
Get down!
Long time no see.